Tiffany Lastimosa

Software Engineer | Bellevue, WA 98005 - open to relocation

☐ lastimosa.ti@gmail.com ☐ github.com/tifflastimosa ☐ linkedin.com/in/tiffanylast

Summary

Former Paralegal transitioning into a Software Engineer role with a computer science graduate degree and over seven years of diverse experience in team collaboration, communication, analysis, and providing solutions. Currently seeking opportunities in fullstack and backend development.

Skills

Languages: Java, JavaScript (ES6), C, Python, SQL, HTML, CSS Databases: MySQL, MongoDB, Firebase, Firestore, Redis

Frameworks | Libraries: Spring Boot, React, Node.js, Express

IDE | Technologies: IntelliJ, VS Code, Postman, Git, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, RabbitMQ, Linux, APIs Agile Methodology, Scrum, Test Driven Development, Unit Testing, API Testing

Projects

Skier Resort Scalable Distributed System

September 2022 - December 2022

Jakarta EE(J2EE), Apache Tomcat, Redis, RabbitMQ, AWS, EC2, Elastic Load Balancing

- Designed a highly scalable microservice by deploying an Apache Tomcat application server, message queue, Redis, and Java programs to over seven instances and applying a network load balancer.
- Evaluated and experimented with different designs, instance types, and schemas to maximize throughput and achieved an average of 40 ms response time and 100% success rate in a pool of 200,000 POST requests.
- Wrote a multithreaded client to send 200,000 POST requests and compute throughput statistics.

Quantified Self Web Application

May 2021 - August 2021

Java, MongoDB, Spring Boot, React, JavaScript, Junit 4, CodeMR, Postman

- Led a team of two developers in an agile environment to build a fullstack REST application with the client-server model and MVC architecture.
- Applied design patterns to parse over 1,600 JSON objects from wearable technology and wrote data to MongoDB.
- Programmed front-end to display three data sets with over ten different graph designs.
- Ran CodeMR reports to measure the quality of source code and attained a software quality average of 70%.
- Applied a test-driven development approach to achieve response time of requests below 200 ms.

Work Experience

Software Engineering Tutor – Freelance | Online

August 2022 - Present

- Taught over ten students to strengthen students' Java, JavaScript, and MySQL programming skills and confidence.
- Initiated and managed students lesson plans for assignments that resulted in a grade higher than 90%.

Paralegal - Seattle Litigation Group, PLLC | Seattle, WA

April 2018 - August 2022

- Partnered with three attorneys to draft documents and communications with opposing parties and clients.
- Fostered over 50 client relationships to collect information and documents and explain the legal process.
- Implemented case management software to modernize the law firm's operations by automating legal document drafting, control redundant data, and integrate data sharing.
- Shortened client onboarding process from 2 hours to 30 minutes to enhance client satisfaction.

Computer Science Teaching Assistant - Northeastern University | Seattle, WA

May 2021 - May 2022

- Held weekly office hours to coach students through their homework design and concepts covered in lectures.
- Facilitated labs to guide over 40 students in understanding concepts of Java and object-oriented design.
- Reviewed code and design to grade homework and labs for up to ten students.
- Improved students understanding of the software development process and use of git operations.

Education

Northeastern University - Khoury College of Computer Sciences.

September 2020 - December 2022

Master of Science in Computer Science | GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

Relevant Courses: Object-Oriented Programming (OO Design), Data Structures and Algorithms, Database Management Systems, Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, Building Scalable Distributed Systems, Fundamentals of Cloud Computing

University of Washington

September 2008 - June 2013

Bachelor of Arts in Anthropology: Medical Anthropology and Global Health, Minor in Diversity